Olivier Brewaeys



olivier@olbrew.me



0032476474957



linkedin.com/in/olbrew



https://olbrew.me

Summary

My experience lies in leading technical teams and providing technical guidance. I'm at my best translating real-world business needs into technological solutions with and for a team. A great user-experience, security and maintainable code are important for me and contribute to both the end-user and developers' happiness. I am ambitious and driven with a never-ending curiosity which always keeps me learning.

Experience



Technical Consultant

Olbrew

Nov 2020 - Present (2 months +)

Technical guidance for non-IT customers, building websites, advice on project management, smaller technical projects such as connecting APIs.

R Technical Lead

Rita Personal Data

Aug 2020 - Nov 2020 (4 months)

Worked on setting out a technical roadmap, hiring developers and start building a mobile app. Did code reviews, setup build processes, project guidelines and guiding the developers.

Rita believes in a democratised data economy, where any internet user can access their data without effort and providing them with a secure way of understanding and managing their personal data.

R Technical Consultant

Rita Personal Data

Sep 2019 - Aug 2020 (1 year)

I helped non-technical core team to assess code quality delivered by external contractors, fix bugs, setup better practices to improve code quality and setting out a technical roadmap.

Project Manager

Lemon Companies

Feb 2019 - Aug 2020 (1 year 7 months)

Managing multiple software projects from initial conversations with clients until commissioning of delivered software, working closely with clients to understand requirements, designers to develop products and software engineers to build the solution.

Managed large development team with up to 10 developers. Tasks included business and technical analysis, project management & product development.

Managed their largest project until then for Big-Four accounting client delivering complete billing management software solution for their internal use. Working with multiple internal client stakeholders such as the business customer and their IT and security teams.

Software Engineer

Lemon Companies

Nov 2018 - Feb 2019 (4 months)

Responsible for maintaining our existing software solutions and supporting the clients use at multinatational companies. Wrote proposals for incoming clients and planned these projects.

Data Privacy Officer

Deltaworx

Mar 2018 - Nov 2018 (9 months)

To satisfy the requirements of the GDPR law and minimise business risk I analysed data flows and secured them by encrypting data in transit and at rest. I organised presentations to educate our employees on the law and created tools to delete data when asked for.

Lead Developer

Deltaworx

Apr 2017 - Nov 2018 (1 year 8 months)

Managed and worked with IT team on a React Native app for students and a back-office planning tool in PHP. Split time between coding and managing the team. Setup AWS environment for serving backend systems and was end-responsible for its uptime.

Deltaworx is a leading student job agency using digital solutions to better match students to employers.

Co-Founder & CTO

Oxysnap

Jan 2016 - Mar 2017 (1 year 3 months)

I did the initial development of a web-based prototype and later a mobile app and was responsible for hiring and project management.

Oxysnap would allow photographers to instantly share their pictures during events or big occassions.

Education

University of Antwerp

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science

2011 - 2016

Academic bachelor in Computer Science with focus on the science behind Software, Languages, Operating Systems, Networks.

Worked on many practical projects such as building our own compiler, implementing a network RFC and fullstack web-applications.

Courses included Algorithms & Complexity, Data Structures, Artificial Intelligence, Computer networks, Databases, Languages & Automata, Calculus, Algebra, Physics, Statistics and Economy.

u∕m Universidad Autónoma de Madrid

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science

2016 - 2017

Erasmus programme